(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#沙花叉クロヱ生誕祭LIVE
#SakamataChloeBirthdayLIVE
さん！
Three!
にー！
Two!
いち！
One!
ラブレター
Love Letter
初めまして 大好きな音楽へ
Nice to meet you, my beloved music.
ずっと考えてたこと
Something I've been thinking about for a long time,
どうか聞いてほしくて
I wanted you to listen to it somehow.
(伝えたいことがあるんです)
(There's something I want to tell you.)
ちょっと照れ臭いけれど
It's a bit embarrassing, but
ずっと想っていたこと
it's something I've always felt.
こんなお手紙に込めて
I put it into this letter,
(届いてくれますように)
(hoping it reaches you.)
どんな時もあなたの 言葉、声を聴いているだけで
No matter when, just by listening to your words and voice,
力が湧いてくるんだ
strength wells up within me.
ねえ笑っていたいよどんな時も
Hey, I want to keep smiling no matter what.
でも辛いくらい痛い日もある
But there are days that hurt so much it's hard.
けどね あなたに触れるだけで気付けば
But you know, just by being close to you, I realize
この世界が色鮮やかになる 花が咲くように
that this world becomes colorful, like flowers blooming.
笑って泣いてどんな時だって
Laughing, crying, at any time,
選んでいいんだいつでも自由に
you're free to choose however you want.
今日はどんなあなたに出会えるかな
I wonder what kind of you I'll meet today.
この世界が終わるその日まで 鳴り続けていて
Until the day this world ends, please keep on ringing out.
いつもあなたのことを求めてしまうんだ
I always find myself seeking you.
(踊り出したくなる時も)
(Even when I want to start dancing,)
(爆発しちゃいそうな時も)
(even when I feel like I'm about to explode.)
救われたんだ 支えられてきたんだ
I've been saved, I've been supported.
(心が動かされるんです)
(My heart is moved,)
(心が満たされていくんです)
(my heart is being filled.)
ねえもっと触れていたいよ ずっとそばにいてほしいよ
Hey, I want to feel you more, I want you by my side forever.
いつまでも大好きなあなたが 響いていますように
I hope you, whom I'll love forever, keep resonating.
...一緒に
...together,
こんなたくさんの気持ち
All of these many feelings,
ぎゅっと詰め込んだ想い
My tightly packed feelings,
ちゃんと伝えられたかな
I wonder if I was able to convey them properly.
ああ ちょっとだけ不安だけど
Ah, I'm just a little bit anxious,
きっと届いてくれたよね
But I'm sure they reached you, right?
全部私の素直な言葉だから
Because they're all my honest words.
もしもあなたに出会えてなかったらなんて
If I had never met you,
思うだけで怖いほど大好きなんだ
The mere thought scares me, that's how much I love you.
受け取ってどうか私の想いを
Please, accept my feelings.
さあ笑って泣いてそんな毎日を
So, laughing and crying through those days,
歩いていくんだいついつまでも
We'll keep walking together, forever and ever.
辛いこと痛いこともたくさんあるけど
There are many painful and hurtful things, but...
この世界はいつでもどこでも音楽で溢れてる
This world is always, everywhere, overflowing with music.
目の前のことも将来のことも不安になってどうしたらいいの
Anxious about what's in front of me and the future, what should I do?
分からなくって迷うこともあるけど
There are times I'm lost and don't know the way, but...
そんな時もきっとあなたがいてくれれば 前を向けるんだ
Even then, I'm sure if you're there, I can look forward.
こんな気持ちになるのは こんな想いができるのは
The reason I feel this way, the reason I can have these thoughts,
きっと音楽だけなんだ
Is surely only because of music.
終わらないひとつもないんです
There's not a single thing that doesn't end.
どうか1000年先も どうか鳴り止まないで
Please, even 1000 years from now, please don't stop ringing.
いつも本当にありがとう
Thank you truly for everything.
君が持ってきたならば
If you were the one who brought it,
花の塔
作詞・作曲 さユり
Flower Tower
Lyrics & Composition: Sayuri
くれた知らない名前のお花
The flower with a name I didn't know that you gave me.
今日はまだ来ないかな
I wonder if it's not coming yet today,
初めての感情知ってしまった
I've come to know a feeling for the first time.
窓に飾った絵画も覗いて一人で宇宙を旅して
Looking at the paintings by the window, traveling through space alone,
それだけでいいはずだったのに
That should have been enough, and yet...
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I ended up holding your hand,
孤独を知らないこの街には
To this town that doesn't know loneliness,
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのでしょう
I probably can't ever return again.
君が手を差し伸べた 光で影が生まれる
You reached out your hand, and light gives birth to shadows.
歌って聴かせて この話の続き
Sing to me, tell me the continuation of this story,
連れてって 見たことない星まで
Take me away, to a star I've never seen before.
誰もここへも届かない 高く聳え立ったこの塔で
Where no one can reach, in this tower standing tall and high,
飛ばす風船 僕は君に笑ってほしいの
Releasing balloons, I want you to smile.
満たされないまま 聖域の合間を濡らした体温で
With an unfulfilled heart, with a body temperature that wetted the sanctuary gaps,
これまでは埋めてきたけれど
I've been filling it up until now, but...
退屈な日々を蹴散らして 君と二人でこの街中を
Kicking away the boring days, if the two of us through this town...
泳ぎきったら それはどれだけ素敵なことでしょう
Managed to swim through, how wonderful would that be?
出したことないほど大きな声で
With a voice louder than I've ever produced,
やっと君に伝わる
It finally reaches you.
歪な空が咲き ちょっといいな
A distorted sky blooms, it's kinda nice,
世界の端と端を結んで
Connecting the edges of the world.
窓に飾った絵画も覗いて一人で宇宙を旅して
Looking at the paintings by the window, traveling through space alone,
それだけで不自由ないけれど
I have no inconveniences with just that, but...
僕ら選んでみたみたい 儚い心 傷だらけの空を
It seems we've tried choosing a transient heart and a sky full of wounds.
…さえも不都合　今は
...even that is inconvenient, so now
書き換えて
rewrite it.
君の手を握ってしまったら
If I end up holding your hand,
孤独を知らないこの街には
in this city that knows no loneliness,
もう二度と帰って来ることはできないでしょう
I probably won't be able to return ever again.
いくらでも迷いながら
While getting lost as much as it takes,
光も影も見に行こう
let's go see both the light and the shadows.
歌って聴かせて　この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story.
連れて行って見たことない星まで
Take me away to stars I've never seen before.
世界の端と端を結んで
Connecting the ends of the world together.
TALKING BOX REMIX
WE CAN GROW UP
CALLING NIGHT
DANCE WITH ME / DANCE WITH YOU
COUNT DOWN
SHUTTLE DOWN
TO BE CONTINUED...
イェーイ！皆、今日お祝いしに来てくれて
Yeah! Everyone, thank you so much for
ありがとうございます！
coming to celebrate today!
イェイイェイイェイイェイ！どうだった？
Yay yay yay yay! How was it?
どうだった？
How was it?
なんかさ、一周年のときよりは緊張しなかった。
You know, I wasn't as nervous as I was during my first anniversary.
何だろうな、いっぱい練習したし。
I wonder why... I practiced a lot.
直前までリハもやってたし、いっぱい練習したし。
I was doing rehearsals until right before, and I practiced a lot.
前と、でもそうか、条件変わんないか。
The conditions haven't really changed since before... wait, I guess they haven't.
変わんないけどなんかすごい緊張しなかったです。
They haven't changed, but for some reason, I wasn't nervous at all.
イェイイェイイェイイェイ！どうだった？
Yay yay yay yay! How was it?
良かった？ありがとうございます。
Was it good? Thank you so much.
ちょっと「ラブレター」は、みんなに対してね、初めましてっていう
For 'Love Letter', it was about that feeling of 'nice to meet you'
その一曲目ってので「初めまして」っていう気持ちとかね。
since it was the first song.
あとみんなに、こういう思いがあるんだよっていうのを伝えたいなと思って選びました。
I chose it because I wanted to tell everyone that I have these feelings.
そして二曲目の「花の塔」もですね、非常に可愛らしい曲で、
And the second song, 'Hana no Tou', is also a very lovely song.
沙花叉めっちゃリコリコ好きでさ、この曲超好きなんだけど。
Sakamata loves LycoReco, and I really love this song.
これもね、なんかみんなと一緒にね、走り出すじゃないけど、
With this one too, it's like we're starting to run together...
これからもね、傍にいたいなっていう気持ちも込めてしました。
I put in my feelings of wanting to be by your side from now on as well.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
あ、ここ、揺れがすごかったですね、はい。
Ah, the swaying here was incredible, wasn't it? Yes.
そしてですね、えー、3曲目『Talking Box』はですね...
And then, um, the 3rd song, "Talking Box"...
あれ、めっちゃ良くない？
Wasn't that one really good?
なんか、さらっと挟まる矢継ぎ早。
Like, those rapid-fire lines tucked in so smoothly.
ね、めちゃくちゃ...
It's really...
めちゃくちゃいいですよ。あれもね、すごい頑張って撮りましたので。
...really great. We worked really hard on recording that one too.
はい、見てもらえて嬉しいな、なんて思っております。みんな、ありがとね。よかったですよ。
I'm really happy you all got to see it. Thanks, everyone. It was good.
ではですね、えー、沙花叉クロヱ、今日お誕生日ということで、みんなにね、たくさんお祝いしてほしいのですがな...
So then, um, since it's Sakamata Chloe's birthday today, I want everyone to celebrate a lot...
えー、お祝いするときのツイートのタグはですね、こちらです。じゃじゃじゃーん。
...but the hashtag for your celebratory tweets is this one. Ta-da!
見えるか？
Can you see it?
こちら、#沙花叉クロヱ生誕祭LIVE で、
Please tweet using
つぶやいてください。
#SakamataChloeBirthdayCelebrationLIVE.
ぜひトレンド1位にしてください。お願いしますお願いしますお願いします。
Please get it to #1 on trending. Please, please, please.
絶対絶対絶対ね。絶対絶対。
Definitely, definitely, definitely, okay? Definitely.
ふぅ... さ、ということでですね、ちょっと、疲れてきちゃったんですけども。早いんですけど、まだ。
Phew... So... anyway, I'm getting a little tired. It's a bit early for that, though.
ちょっとね、なんか、また、知ってるような気がするんですけど、ちょっととあるものをですね、
You know, I feel like I've seen this before, but...
水族館に特別に用意してくださったらしく。ちょっと移動しちゃいますか？
...apparently, they've prepared something special for me at the aquarium. Shall we head over?
移動させていただきまーす。
I'll be moving now.
ちょっと、じゃあ水族館にみんなで行くぞー。行きますよー。
Alright, everyone, let's go to the aquarium together! Here we go!
パパパパーン、パパパパーン...
(Humming transition music...)
ヌヌヌ... ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って...
Nu-nu-nu... Wait a second, wait a second...
沙花叉からのラブレター、読んでほしいな。
I want you to read this love letter from Sakamata.
はい、これ。
Here, take this.
飼育員さんへ
To my Keepers,
いつも応援してくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always supporting me!
沙花叉は飼育員さんのことが
Sakamata loves...
だいすきだよ！
...her Keepers!
これからも、沙花叉のこと
From now on, too...
ずっと見ててね。
...please keep an eye on Sakamata.
おうえんしてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for supporting me.
だいすきだよ！
I love you!
♡沙花叉クロヱ♡
♡Sakamata Chloe♡
2023.11.16
はい、ということで、移動してきましたー。どうもどうもどうもー。
Alright, we've arrived! Hello, hello, hello!
沙花叉からのラブレター、読んでくれましたか？どうだった？
Did you read the love letter from Sakamata? How was it?
沙花叉ね、ちょっと頑張って書いたんですけど、あの、こんな2分半も使われるとは思っていませんでした。
I worked pretty hard on that, but I didn't think it would take up two and a half minutes.
皆さん、2分半の間ね、読めたかと思うんですけども。はい、ありがとうございます。
I hope you all managed to read it during those two and a half minutes. Yes, thank you very much.
ではですね、ちょっと、ど、どうですか、この水族館？
So then, um, what do you think of this aquarium?
皆さん、あの、ちょっと知ってる人は知っている、なんですけど、
Some of you might recognize it, but...
実はね、沙花叉、水族館イベントをやっていたんですが、最近。
...actually, I was holding an aquarium event recently.
そのね、元になったアクアパーク品川さんを元にして、このステージを作ったんですけど。
We built this stage based on Aqua Park Shinagawa, which was the venue for that event.
水族館のね、その時の映像も、もう行けなかったよっていう子のために用意しております。
I've also prepared some footage from the aquarium for those who couldn't make it.
あれ？
Wait, what's this?
さらっと出せよ。
Just pop it out.
あれ、あれ？このボタンは...
Wait, what? These buttons...
あれれれー、もしやーっていうやつですかね。
Oh-ho-ho, could it be one of those things?
お誕生日ライブといえばやっぱり…
When it comes to a birthday live, it has to be...
スロットだよね！
A slot machine!
いいんですか、これ？マジで？
Is this okay? Seriously?
よし、絶対スロットだろうということで。
Alright, it just had to be a slot machine.
じゃあ、ちょっと行きますよ。
Okay, here I go.
電源、オーン！
Power, ON!
あれ？
Huh?
つかない。
It's not turning on.
つかない？
Not turning on?
音がない。
There's no sound.
電源、オーン！
Power, ON!
あれ、つかない。
Wait, it's still not on.
クソっ、何でだ？
Damn it, why?
何か、つかないぞ。
Something's not right.
電源が足りてない？
Is there not enough power?
じゃあ、もう最後、気合の蹴りで行くわ。
Fine, one last kick with all my might!
電源、オーン！
Power, ON!
あ、ついたー！
Oh, it's on!
あー焦った。事故ったかと思った。
Phew, that was scary. I thought it crashed.
はい。ではですね。坂又恒例のスロットタイムということで、回します！
Alright then. It's time for Sakamata's traditional slot time! Spinning!
はっ！
Ha!
あ、BAR来てる。ほい！
Oh, a BAR symbol. There!
えっ？
Eh?
うわー！フリーズ引いちゃったんだけど！
Whoa! I hit a Freeze!
えー！大丈夫！？
Wait, is this okay?!
このスロットやばすぎない？壊れ台なんだけど！
Isn't this slot machine too crazy? It's rigged!
フリーズ引きましたね。
I actually hit a Freeze.
ちょっと、坂又もしかして、しょっぱなから当たってる？
Wait, did Sakamata just win right from the start?
え？これ、当たってるってこと？
Eh? Does this mean I won?
みんな、いいんですか？あ、何だ。
Everyone, is this really okay? Oh, wait.
何だ。ただのバグか。
Oh, it's just a bug.
あ、そうですね。はい。じゃあ次だ。
Ah, right. Okay, next one.
まあ、しょてからのさ、2回目のこの真ん中で大体わかるんよ。
Well, usually you can tell by the second reel in the middle.
当たんないなとかさ。
Like, 'I'm not gonna win'...
当たるなとか。あ、おい！
...or 'I'm gonna win'. Hey!
お？やや？
Oh? Wait?
はい。
Okay.
まあまあまあまあ。
Now, now, now.
どうなんすか？
How is it?
ねえ！坂又のスロット壊れてるって！
Hey! Sakamata's slot machine is broken!
おいおいおいおい！ちょっと遊びたいのに！
Hey, hey! I just want to play a bit!
ひどい！ひどい！ちょっと！
This is mean! So mean!
どういうことなんですか？
What is the meaning of this?
このホール訴えますよ！
I'm going to sue this establishment!
なあ！上場したんだろ？訴えてやる！
Hey! You went public, didn't you? I'll sue you!
じゃ、回しますよ！
Alright, spinning again!
はっ！
Ha!
スイカ来てるよ！え？
A watermelon's coming! Eh?
これスイカ？
Is this a watermelon?
どっちだ、どっちだ。
Which one, which one?
おおー！
Ohhh!
ちゃんとスイカ拾いましたね。BARじゃないやつや。
I actually got a watermelon. Not the BAR one.
え、これはもしや来るのでは。
Wait, is this what I think it is?
はっ！クロヱチャレンジ！？何それ！？
Ha! Chloe Challenge?! What's that?!
そんなん、作ったの？ねえ。
You made something like that? Hey.
ちゃんと打ってる人じゃん。え？
You're a real pro. Eh?
え、これしかもHoloXのロゴやん、後ろについてるの。
And look, that's the HoloX logo in the back.
何、クロヱチャレンジ？
What is this Chloe Challenge?
え、どうなるの？どうなるの？
Whoa, what happens next?
いいんですか、これ？
Is this really okay?
入るのかな、クロヱチャレンジに。
Am I entering the Chloe Challenge?
あ！うわー、なるほどね。こっちからか。
Ah! Whoa, I see. From this side.
はいはいはい、右からね。
Okay, okay, from the right.
7を狙え！はい！
Aim for the 7! Yes!
はい！乗ってる！
Yes! It's on!
はい！いいんじゃない！？
Yes! Looking good!
はい！来い来い来い来い来い！
Come on, come on, come on!
あ！あ！虹だ！
Ah! It's rainbow!
確定演出！確定でしょこれ！
A guaranteed win! This has to be a win!
でもたまに虹で外れるよね？どっち！？
But sometimes even rainbow misses, right? Which is it?!
え？
Eh?
入るかな？入っちゃうかな？
Will I win? Am I gonna win?
お誕生日だけど、入っちゃうかな？
It's my birthday, so maybe I'll win?
やれやれ！どうなる！？うわー！
Let's go! What's gonna happen?! Whoa!
虹色って言ってたのに！嘘つき！
It was rainbow, but it missed! Liar!
へ！？フリーズ！？えええ！？
Huh?! A Freeze?! Whaaat?!
フリーズできた！これ！えええー！
I got a Freeze! Look at this! Whaaaat!
えっ、えっ！？フリーズ演出！
Wait, wait! A Freeze effect!
うわああ！当たってる！
Waaaah! I'm winning!
へ！？ちょっと待って、発展したんだけど！
Huh?! Wait a minute, it's evolving!
発展とかあんの、このスロットに！？
This slot machine has evolutions?!
ええ！何！？
Whaaaat! What's this?!
すごい！金色の、金色の役が！
Amazing! Golden... golden symbols!
ねえ！どうなるんだい！？
Hey! What's gonna happen?!
頼む！7で頼む！
Please! Give me a 7!
7！7！7！7！7！頼む！
7! 7! 7! 7! 7! Please!
トリプルセブンで頼む！頼むー！
Give me a Triple Seven! I'm begging you!
ポチポチ...
Click click...
せいっ！
There!
き、きたああああ！
I-It's here!
きたきたきたきたあああああ！
It's here, it's here, it's here!
やったあああああ！
I did it!
あ、当たった...
Ah, I won...
トリプルセブン
歌唱：沙花叉クロヱ
作詞・作曲：浅野尚志
Triple Seven
Vocals: Sakamata Chloe
Lyrics/Composition: Takashi Asano
いっしょに？ うーーかもん！
Together? Ooh, come on!
ホロライブから　こんにちは
Hello from Hololive.
うまくいきすぎちゃって　すいません
Sorry for being too successful.
追い風びゅううっと背に受けて
Receiving the tailwind on my back,
いくぜ！とんとんとんとん拍子で
here I go! Smoothly,
Go! Go! Go! Go!
ぴちぴちはねるぜ　名古屋城
Leaping energetically, Nagoya Castle.
くるくるぱっと回って　のぼり龍
Spinning around quickly, a rising dragon.
センパイ方のチカラ借り
Borrowing power from my seniors,
ノってみせるぜどデカいビッグウェーブ！
I'll ride the huge big wave!
ねえわたしたち　ほんとツイてるから
Hey, we're really lucky,
ぜんぶラッキーラッキーラッキー
so everything is lucky, lucky, lucky.
ラッキーラッキーラッキー
Lucky, lucky, lucky.
いただいちゃいます！
I'll take it!
今日もカクヘンがとまらない！
The jackpot mode won't stop today too!
キセキを起こしまくれ！
Keep making miracles happen!
いっさいがっさい　いただいちゃえ！
Take everything!
運も実力のうちだもんね
Luck is also a part of skill, right?
あれもこれもそれもどれも
This, that, and everything else,
欲しくなってこまっちゃう
I want them all and it's troubling.
かっさらっちゃえ！
Snatch them up!
ごちそうさま！
Thank you for the meal!
神サマもーーっとくださいな
God, please give me more.
トリプルセブン
Triple Seven
なななな！　なななな！
Seven-seven! Seven-seven!
(とーぶーよっ！)
(We're flying!)
おしとやかなフリしてみても
Even if I pretend to be ladylike,
熱いハートはいつも燃えさかる
my passionate heart is always burning.
この世の道理はガッテン承知
I understand the ways of the world.
どんなラッキーも勝手にはやってこない！
No luck comes on its own!
みんなホントはモー特訓してるんだ
Everyone is actually doing intense training,
そうさ
that's right.
ゼッタイぜったい　ぜったい
Surely, surely, surely,
願いは叶う！
wishes will come true!
今日もカクヘンを止めさせない！
I won't let the jackpot mode stop today either!
キセキをたぐり寄せろ！
Pull miracles towards you!
あそれヒッパレ！　そりゃアッパレ！
Ah, pull it! That's wonderful!
運は努力でつかみとるんだ
Luck is grabbed through effort.
君がいるからがんばれる
Because you are here, I can do my best.
今すぐにお返ししたい！
I want to pay you back right now!
あげるよラッキー！　みんなでハッピー！
I'll give you luck! Happy together!
ずっと当て続けてみせる
I'll keep hitting the jackpot forever.
トリプルセブン
Triple Seven
なななな！　なななな！
Seven-seven! Seven-seven!
なななななな！
Seven-seven-seven!
もしもいいことなくたってね
Even if nothing good happens,
そのぶんっでっかいラッキーが
a huge amount of luck...
君のこと待っているんだよ
...is waiting for you
今夜は
tonight.
信じ続けていればきっといつかいいことあるさ
If you keep believing, surely something good will happen someday.
この気持ち君にとどけたいから
Because I want to deliver this feeling to you,
君の声たくさんききたいから
because I want to hear your voice a lot.
もっともっともっともっともっと
More and more and more and more and more,
ツイてきて！
follow me!
もう　もう　とめられな～～い！！
Already, already, I can't be stopped!!
今日もカクヘンがとまらない！
The jackpot mode won't stop today too!
キセキを起こしまくれ！
Keep making miracles happen!
いっさいがっさい　いただいちゃえ！
Take everything!
運も実力のうちだもんね
Luck is also a part of skill, right?
あれもこれもそれもどれも
This, that, and everything else,
欲しくなってこまっちゃう
I want them all and it's troubling.
かっさらっちゃえ！
Snatch them up!
ごちそうさま！
Thank you for the meal!
神サマもーーっとくださいな
God, please give me more.
トリプルセブン
Triple Seven
なななな！　なななな！
Seven-seven! Seven-seven!
なななななな！
Seven-seven-seven!
君に捧ぐ
Dedicated to you
トリプルセブン！
Triple Seven!
ワン、ツー、サン、シッ！
One, two, three, four!
ポジティブ・パレード
作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Positive Parade
Lyrics/Composition: DECO*27
Hey! 笑顔、涙、流すじゃない？
Hey! You shed smiles and tears, don't you?
それで平気なフリは普通じゃない？
Is pretending to be okay normal after that?
Hey! 辛いことあるのに
Hey! Even though there are painful things,
世界、こんなモヤモヤは特に関係ない
The world doesn't really care about this haziness.
何時、溜息に溢れそう
Always about to overflow with sighs.
これも、もうダメ、助けて
This is no good either, help me.
そう、焦ることもない
That's right, no need to rush.
聞けば、ほら大丈夫
If you listen, see, it's okay.
甘えられない、頼っちゃえ
Can't be coddled? Then just lean on me.
叶えたい夢、胸にギュッと詰めて
Stuff the dreams you want to fulfill tightly into your heart.
したいことばかりで、やってみせて
Show me all the things you want to do.
僕ら止まれない、これは良い感じですか？
We can't stop, does this feel good?
やっぱりダメでしょう
As I thought, it's no good.
終わらない夜は星取って照らそう
Let's light up the endless night with stars.
繋いだ時も光はずっと側に
Even when we're connected, the light is always by our side.
僕ら止まれない、君も大丈夫になる
We can't stop, you'll be okay too.
ぴったり笑顔になるから
Because you'll have a perfect smile.
もっともっと込めちゃって、いいんじゃない？
Isn't it okay to put more and more into it?
言いたい言葉、間違えないよ
I won't mistake the words I want to say.
言い訳をします、僕はここにいます
I'll make an excuse, I am here.
明日に凹まされるように、また笑い合えたら
If we can laugh together again, after being flattened by tomorrow...
叶えたい夢、胸にギュッと詰めて
Stuff the dreams you want to fulfill tightly into your heart.
したいことばかりで、やってみせて
Show me all the things you want to do.
僕ら止まれない、これは良い感じですか？
We can't stop, does this feel good?
やっぱりダメでしょう
As I thought, it's no good.
終わらない夜は星取って照らそう
Let's light up the endless night with stars.
繋いだ時も光はずっと側に
Even when we're connected, the light is always by our side.
僕ら止まれない、君も大丈夫になる
We can't stop, you'll be okay too.
ぴったり笑顔になるから
Because you'll have a perfect smile.
間違ってなんていないのに
Even though I haven't done anything wrong,
ほら、誰がなんて言おうなら
Look, no matter what anyone says,
君を否定しちゃう全てを
Everything that denies you,
放っておいたりしないから
I won't just leave it be.
手締めてついででもいいから
Even if it's just a byproduct of holding hands,
ほら、上手く流してよ
Look, just let it slide properly.
恥ずかしいって言うけれど
You say it's embarrassing,
それは僕も一緒なんだよ
But it's the same for me too.
似合ってないとかは言わないよ
I won't say it doesn't suit you.
君に会った事の答えだ
It's the answer to having met you.
頼ってくれ
Rely on me.
と
And...
叶えたい夢、胸にギュッと詰めて
Stuff the dreams you want to fulfill tightly into your heart.
したいことばかりで、やってみせて
Show me all the things you want to do.
僕ら止まれない、これは良い感じですか？
We can't stop, does this feel good?
やっぱりダメでしょう
As I thought, it's no good.
終わらない夜は星取って照らそう
Let's light up the endless night with stars.
繋いだ時も光はずっと側に
Even when we're connected, the light is always by our side.
僕ら止まれない、君も大丈夫になる
We can't stop, you'll be okay too.
ぴったり笑顔になるから
Because you'll have a perfect smile.
僕ら止まれない
We can't stop.
君も大丈夫になる、ぴったり笑顔になるから
You'll be okay too, because you'll have a perfect smile.
どうだった？
How was that?
ちょっと沙花叉初のゲストということで
Since it's Sakamata's first time having guests...
ホロXに来てもらいました！ありがとうございました！
I had HoloX come over! Thank you all so much!
ちょっとめちゃめちゃ可愛くみんなでね
Everyone looked super cute,
そしてあの、なんか意味を持たせてできたんじゃないかなと思うので
and I think we were able to perform with a certain meaning behind it,
またこれも今度お話しさせてください
so let me talk more about that another time.
で、普段ね、応援してくれてる飼育員さんにもちょっと感謝の気持ちを伝えたいなと思って
And, I wanted to express my gratitude to the Breeders who always support me,
感謝といえばこれですよね！
and when you think of gratitude, it's gotta be this!
じゃーん！花束！
Ta-da! A bouquet!
これ、何だか分かりますかね？
Do you know what this is for?
ちょっと浮かばない？とある曲が...
Doesn't it ring a bell? A certain song...
そしてゴンドラがここにあるというね
And there's even a gondola here.
はい、いきたいと思います。
Alright, here we go.
愛をこめて花束を！
A bouquet with love!
愛をこめて花束を
作詞:多保孝一・いしわたり淳治・越智志帆 / 作曲:多保孝一 / 編曲:蔦谷好位置
A Bouquet with Love
Lyrics: Koichi Tabo, Junji Ishiwatari, Shiho Ochi / Composition: Koichi Tabo / Arrangement: Koichi Tsutaya
二人で写真を撮ろう
Let's take a photo together
懐かしいこの景色と
With this nostalgic scenery
あの人と同じポーズで
In the same pose as that person
おどけて見せてほしい
I want you to show me a playful look
見上げる空の青さ
The blueness of the sky we look up at
気まぐれに雲は流れて
Clouds flow capriciously
綺麗なものは遠くに
Beautiful things are far away
あるから綺麗なの
And that's why they're beautiful
約束した通りに
Just as we promised
ありがとう...
Thank you...
ここにいられて本当によかったわ
I'm so glad to be here
このこみあげる気持ちが愛じゃないなら
If this surging feeling isn't love
何が愛かわからないほど
Then I don't know what love is
愛をこめて花束を 大袈裟だけど受け取って
A bouquet with love, it's exaggerated but please accept it
理由なんて聞かないでよね
Don't ask me for a reason, okay?
今だけすべて忘れて 笑わないで受け止めて
Forget everything just for now, don't laugh and accept it
照れていないで
Don't be shy
昨日とよく似た今日は なにげない別れ道
Today, so similar to yesterday, is a casual fork in the road
分かって選びそびれた 臆病なせいでした
I understood but missed the chance to choose, it was because of my cowardice
私は甘えるのが得意で
I'm good at being pampered
最初から慰めをあてにしてたわ
I was counting on consolation from the start
何度も間違った道 選び続けて
Choosing the wrong path over and over again
正しくここに戻ってきたの
I correctly returned here
巡り巡る時を越え いつもあなたのところへと
Crossing time that goes round and round, always to where you are
この心 舞い戻ってゆく
This heart will come back to you
無理に描く理想より 笑い合える今日の方が
Rather than an ideal drawn by force, today where we can laugh together
ずっと幸せね
Is much happier
Violet, indigo, black and blue
Flame, orange, yellow, purple, sky, blue
Pink, yellow, green, ash, brown
あなたに贈る色は...
The colors I send to you are...
巡り巡る時を越え いつもあなたのところへと
Crossing time that goes round and round, always to where you are
この心 舞い戻ってゆく
This heart will come back to you
ありがとうを言い出せずに 甘えていた今日ここまでは
Without being able to say thank you, I was pampered up until today here
愛をこめて花束を
A bouquet with love
大袈裟だけど受け取って
It's exaggerated but please accept it
理由なんて聞かないでよね
Don't ask me for a reason, okay?
今だけすべて忘れて 笑わないで受け止めて
Forget everything just for now, don't laugh and accept it
本当の私も
Even the real me
いつまでもそばにいて
Stay by my side forever
どうでしたかみんな？
How was it, everyone?
花束受け取ってくれましたか？
Did you receive the bouquet?
沙花叉の気持ち、ちょっと本当に投げさせていただきました。
I really threw Sakamata's feelings at you for a bit.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
いや沙花叉ね、本当に普段からみんなには感謝をしていて、
Well, Sakamata is really grateful to everyone on a regular basis,
ちょっとお言葉を伝えるのが下手っぴなのであんまり言えないのですが、
I'm a bit bad at putting it into words, so I can't say it much, but...
あの、いつもありがとうございます。
Um, thank you always.
大好きです。
I love you.
あ、でもなん誕生日のお祝いなのに、なんか足りないな。
Ah, but even though it's a birthday celebration, something's missing.
もっと、もっとなんかお誕生日感欲しいな。
I want more, more of a birthday feeling.
ね、もっともっと、もっともらえるよね、いいよね？
Right, I can get more, more, it's okay, right?
じゃあ、みんな、言っちゃいますか？
Then, everyone, shall we say it?
ちょっと、次のステージに行っちゃおうかな。
Maybe I'll go to the next stage.
いきまーす！
Here I go!
せーの、レッツゴー！
One, two, let's go!
みんなお祝いしてくれてありがとー！
Thanks for celebrating everyone!
ちょっと沙花叉さ、このお誕生日で一つ強くなったと思うので、
I think Sakamata became one step stronger with this birthday,
皆さんにですね、沙花叉の強くなっちゃったところ、見せちゃいたいと思います！
So I'd like to show you all how Sakamata has become stronger!
あ、お待たせしました、マジで。
Ah, sorry for the wait, really.
坂又ね、なんかあの、振り付けでまだ出てきてないかもしれないんですけど、あの、まだ出てきてないんですけど、
You might not have seen this in my choreography yet, but Sakamata, um...
こういうね、見て見て。
look, look, something like this.
これ、なんか見たことない？みんな。
Doesn't this look familiar to everyone?
反復横跳びですね。あの、ダンサーさんに教わったんですよ。
It's a side shuttle. My dancer taught me.
「反復横跳びの要領でやればいいんですよ」と言われて、
They told me, "Just do it like a side shuttle,"
「反復横跳び...！」って言ったら教えてもらって、
and when I asked, "Side shuttle...?", they taught me.
これ、だからできるの坂又、見てて。行くよ？
So, Sakamata can do it. Watch. Here I go!
せーの！
Ready, set...
はい！はい！はい！はい、はい、はい！はい！はい、はい、はい！ほら、できる！どう？
Hup! Hup! Hup! Hup, hup, hup! Hup! Hup, hup, hup! See, I can do it! How's that?
危ない...できてる？できてるよね？
That was close... Did I do it? I did, right?
成長したくない？ほら！ほらね！
Haven't I grown? Look! See!
いや、だいぶ一回はできるようになった。
Yeah, I've managed to do it at least once.
すごいでしょ？おめでた言って。すごいでしょ？すごいでしょ？
Isn't it amazing? Congratulate me. Amazing, right? Right?
そしてね、あともう一つできるようになったことがあるんですよ。
And there's one more thing I can do now.
側転！
A cartwheel!
行きますよ！
Here I go!
はっ！うわぁっ！
Hah! Whoa!
よし、言ったわ。
Alright, I did it.
完璧でしたね！
That was perfect!
完璧だったよね？みんな。
It was perfect, right, everyone?
あ〜疲れた。あ〜疲れた。座っちゃった。
Ah, I'm tired. I'm so tired. I ended up sitting down.
あ〜すごいわ。あ〜...
Ah, that was something. Ah...
本当にお誕生日本当におめでとう...
Happy birthday, truly...
あ〜みんな本当にありがとうです。
Ah, everyone, thank you so much.
今日はいっぱいお祝いしてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for celebrating so much today.
エゴサもね、坂又してたのですが、
I was checking social media, and...
みんながなんかあの、ケーキを作ってくれたりとか、
everyone was making cakes for me,
あとあれもいたな、あのピクセルアートみたいなすっごいデカやつ作ってくれた方もいたし、
and some made these huge pixel art pieces,
あとね、すっごいグッズの祭壇みたいなの作ってくれた方もいらっしゃったので、
and some even made amazing merchandise shrines.
本当に嬉しかったです。
I was really happy.
これからもね、坂又のことたくさん愛してね！
Please continue to love me lots!
そして今日は本当に緊張の、ガチガチ緊張なので、
And since I'm really, really nervous today,
よかったらみんな、あのコメントでも「見てるよ」「愛してるよ」「頑張れ」って言ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could comment things like "I'm watching", "I love you", or "Good luck".
緊張。
So nervous.
では、あの、坂又頑張りますので、応援よろしくなんだわ！
Well then, I'll do my best, so please support me!
バイバイ！死ぬ。
Bye-bye! I'm gonna die.
はい、というわけでフェスステージにやってきました！イェーイ！
Okay, so we've made it to the Fes stage! Yay!
ちょっと見て見て、これ、凄くない？
Look, look! Isn't this amazing?
フェスステージ、めちゃめちゃカッコいいよね。ロック、ザ・ロックだよね。
The Fes stage is so incredibly cool. It's totally rock.
坂又といえばロックでしょ、みんな。初めて聞いたかもだけど。凄くない？
Sakamata means rock, right? You might be hearing this for the first time, though. Isn't it great?
見て、めっちゃ綺麗なんですけど。凄〜い！
Look, it's so beautiful. Amazing!
しかもね、ちゃんと客席に皆さんがいらっしゃるんですよ。
And what's more, you're all right there in the audience.
ちょっと見れるかな？みんなここに。
Can you see? Everyone is here.
凄い、めちゃめちゃズラーッと。ほらほらほら！うわぁ、相変わらず怖いわ！
Incredible, they're all lined up. Look, look! Whoa, creepy as always!
みんなね、何でそんな顔つけちゃったのかなって毎回思いますね。
I wonder every time why you guys chose those faces.
うわぁ、嫌だな、何度見ても嫌なビジュアルしてます。はい。
Whoa, I don't like it. No matter how many times I see it, it's a creepy visual. Yeah.
というわけでね、この後ちょっとライブをしていきたいんですけど、
So, I'd like to do a live performance after this,
フェスって言ったら、あれ欲しくないですか？あれ。分かるみんな？
but speaking of festivals, don't you want "that"? You know what I mean?
ねぇ、あれ、あれ。みんなちょっと言って、今コメントで。分かるでしょ？あれあれ。
You know, that thing. Everyone, tell me in the comments. You know what it is, right?
あれ欲しいよね！フェスと言えば何ですか？大喜利じゃないからね？フェスと言えば？なんだ！
We want that! What do you associate with festivals? It's not a joke segment, okay? Festivals mean...? What is it!
そう、なになに、みんなフェス思う？大丈夫かな？分かってるかな？
That's right, what do you guys think of? Is it okay? Do you understand?
「サイリウム」！あ〜違うね。まあ、サイリウム振るタイプのフェスもあるけどね。分かる分かる。はい。
"Lightsticks"! Ah, no. Well, there are festivals where people wave lightsticks. I get it. Yeah.
あ、そう！えっ、よく分かったね！そうなんですよ。
Ah, yes! Oh, you got it right! That's it.
これなんだ？これみんな。これなんだこれ？
What's this? Everyone. What's this?
そう！ギターなんですよ！ギター欲しいの、坂又。
Yes! It's a guitar! I want a guitar.
ちょっと運営さん、みんなも言ってるし坂又も欲しいから、あのお誕生日プレゼントにギターください、ギター。ギター。
Management, everyone is saying it and I want one too, so please give me a guitar as a birthday present. A guitar. A guitar.
おっ？宝箱だ！えっ、やった！もらえるってこと？
Oh? A treasure chest! Yes! Does that mean I get it?
あ、鍵。鍵付いてるんだけど。えっ、鍵は？
Ah, a key. It's locked. Eh, where's the key?
鍵...ねぇ、鍵は？
The key... hey, where's the key?
沙花叉ギターゲットチャレンジ
Sakamata Guitar Get Challenge
えっ！？
Eh!?
「沙花叉ギターゲットチャレンジ」！？
"Sakamata Guitar Get Challenge"!?
ねぇ、そういうのいい、そういうのいいから、ちょうだい！ねぇ、今欲しいの！ねぇ、何それっていうか、何、何させられるのまず？
Hey, enough of that, just give it to me! I want it now! I mean, what is that, and what are you going to make me do?
それ次第じゃね？
Depends on that, right?
大爆笑！画像大喜利10連発
Hilarious! 10-round Image Ohgiri
ふざけんな！
Don't mess with me!
ふざけんな！「大爆笑」なんて文字を使うな、そんで。えー！
Don't mess with me! And don't use the word "Hilarious"! Ehh!
これ、ど、ど、どうしたらいいの？
What, what, what should I do with this?
え、沙花叉が画像大喜利を10連発すんの？
What, Sakamata has to do 10 image Oogiri in a row?
何それ地獄の時間？ちょっとやめてもらっていいですか？
What's with this hellish segment? Can you please stop?
歌いたいな～、なんか何度も歌いたくなる
I want to sing... I feel like singing over and over again.
分かりました、じゃあ、行きますか？
Alright, well, shall we go?
あの、1枚目とか、あるんですかね？1枚目どうぞ！
So, is there a first one? First image, please!
そろそろこのお好み焼き焼くのも飽きてきたな～
I'm starting to get tired of cooking this okonomiyaki...
2枚目！
Second image!
あ、最近老眼入ってんだよな～
Ah, my presbyopia has been kicking in lately...
老眼入ってんだよな～！な！老眼入ってんだよな～！
Presbyopia's kicking in! Right! Presbyopia's kicking in!
厳しいな！はい次！
That's tough! Okay, next!
バック・トゥ・ザ・フューチャー！
Back to the Future!
出ないか、そうだよね、良くないしね、はい次！
Didn't work? Right, it's not good anyway. Next!
なんだこの時間！
What is this segment?!
え、待って次、次、次、次！
Wait, next, next, next, next!
あなたを殺せば、最後なのよね？
If I kill you, it'll be the last one, right?
ダメ？痛い… ああ… くそ、次！
No? Ouch... Ah... Dammit, next!
見て見て、親知らず生えた！
Look, look! My wisdom tooth came in!
お、いけた！え、嘘、誰が笑った、今ので！
Oh, it worked! Wait, really? Who laughed at that?!
えーいけるんだ！え、やった！親知らずでいけました、やった！
Wow, it worked! Yay! I passed with a wisdom tooth joke!
え、なに、なんか、せっかくだからもうちょっとウケてくださいって言われたんだけど… よし、はいどうぞ、どうぞ！
Wait, they told me to try and be funnier since we're here... Alright, go ahead, next!
もう全部使いたいのね、尺を。はい。
You just want to use up all the time, don't you. Fine.
家族の命が、かかってるんだ！
My family's lives are on the line!
あーいいんだ、それもいいんだ。それも許されるんだ、はい。はい次。
Oh, that's okay too? That's allowed? Fine. Next.
何だこれ。
What is this even.
ああ…分かんない、同じ気持ちになっていいよって感じだけど
Ah... I don't know, it's like 'feel free to feel the same way'...
分かんないよ、むずい、何やらされてんの！
I don't know! It's hard! What are you making me do!
スロット、打ってらっしゃる？あー…
Are you playing slots? Ah...
いや、打ちたいんだけどな、黒字なんだけどなー
Well, I want to play, but I'm already in the black...
あ、いいんだ、それもいいんだ。へー、基準が分からんな。なんか、しょうもないなーと思っても通る、意外と。
Oh, that's okay? Really? I don't get the criteria. It passes even if it's lame.
ラストらしいです。
Apparently, it's the last one.
これすればエサもらえるんだよな～
If I do this, I'll get some food...
OK！沙花叉の気持ちでした。
OK! That's how Sakamata feels.
これすればエサもらえるんだよな～、ありがとうございました、どうも。
If I do this, I'll get food. Thank you very much.
地獄の企画に付き合わせてしまい、すみません。本当に、あの、事前に何も教えてもらわずに、いきなりバンって出されたやつなんで、沙花叉も動揺しておりますが。
Sorry for making you sit through that hellish segment. Honestly, I wasn't told anything beforehand, it was just suddenly thrown at me, so I'm flustered too.
これでじゃあ沙花叉、鍵ゲットしたんですか？え、ちょうだい！ちょうだい、ちょうだい、鍵は！
So, with this, did Sakamata get the key? Hey, give it to me! Give it, give it! The key!
鍵もらいたいの、沙花叉。あ！
I want the key. Ah!
持ってる！すごーい！
I have it! Amazing!
え、じゃあこれ開けれる？ギターもらえるの、沙花叉？
Wait, so I can open this? Does Sakamata get the guitar?
へ、へ、へ、あ、せーの、ガチャ！
Hehe... alright, ready, set, open!
通せんぼせんぞ、捕まえたくない…
I won't block the way, I don't want to catch you...
サマリー箱を開けました。
I opened the summary box!
おおーすごーい！いいんですかこれ？ええー！
Whoa, amazing! Is this for real? Wow!
あざまーす！入ってたー！
Thank you! It was inside!
かっこよくない？すごーい！ギターもろた、もろた、もろたー！
Isn't it cool? Amazing! I got a guitar, I got it, I got it!
では、次の曲、ギターを弾きながら行きたいと思います。
Now, for the next song, I'll be playing the guitar while I sing.
行きます。聴いてください。
Here we go. Please listen.
Perfect Crime.
Perfect Crime
作詞・作曲: 吾由 / 編曲: THE 118's
Lyrics & Composition: Ayu / Arrangement: THE 118's
Perfect Crime
作詞・作曲: 百合　編曲: THE 118's
Lyrics/Composition: Yuri, Arrangement: THE 118's
あたしのブラックリストです
It's my blacklist
愛していたのです
I was in love with you
嫌いな人なんです
You're someone I hate
あたしだけに優しい
You're kind only to me
あたしを可愛いと言ってくれる
You tell me I'm cute
あたしのこと一番と言ってくれる
You tell me I'm your number one
あたししか愛せないはず
You're only supposed to love me
あたしを綺麗にしてくれる
You make me beautiful
あたしの為に死ねる
You'd die for me
あたしが居ないと眠れない
You can't sleep without me
あたしの声を聞かないと生きられない
You can't live without hearing my voice
あたしにしか縋れないはず
You're only supposed to cling to me
あたしの為に生まれてきたなら
If you were born for my sake...
あたしの為に死ねよ
...then die for my sake
病める時も
In sickness...
健やかなる時も
...and in health
富める時も
For richer...
貧しき時も
...or for poorer
愛し敬い慈しむことを誓いますと
I vow to love, honor, and cherish you...
言え
Say it
愛しそして壊す
Love, and then destroy
擬態ごっこ
作詞・作曲: DECO*27　編曲: Rockwell
Mimicry Play
Lyrics/Composition: DECO*27, Arrangement: Rockwell
笑ってるけどどっか無いんだ
I'm laughing, but something's missing
痛みがご褒美の日な
A day where pain is the reward
思ってるけどずっと溜めてんだ
I'm thinking about it, but I've been bottling it up
蜜の味呪いの愛が
The taste of honey, the cursed love...
すり減って濁って I love myself
...worn down and muddied, I love myself
伝ってそうやって籠もって不感症
Tracing it, that way, shutting myself in, frigidity
補ってキスをしてみるけど
I try to make up for it with a kiss, but...
渇いた御誂え向きってなんだ
...what is this parched "just right" feeling?
擬態ごっこいいねもっと
Mimicry play, it's good, give me more
つまんない嘘ばかりのシンデレラ
A Cinderella full of boring lies
叶えたい消えたい歪んでいくんだ
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's all warping
境界線
Boundary line
どれも正解で
Everything is the right answer
叶えたい消えたい歪んでいくんだ
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's all warping
君だけには教えてもいいかな
I wonder if I can tell only you
Far in the world of myself, to myself / World in my own psycho
I'm going where I'd rather go / Or maybe I just move tomorrow
強がって　尖っちゃって　愛を演じて
Acting tough, getting prickly, performing love
気になっちゃって　壊したくなるの才能
Obsessing over it, I have a talent for wanting to break things
欲しがっちゃって　後悔して
Wanting it, then regretting it
変わったつもりが嫌になるんだ
Hating myself for thinking I'd changed
財産は端から溜まった劣等
Wealth is the inferiority accumulated from the start
1歩を消して　そろそろ息した
Erasing a step, finally taking a breath
レトロでどうかした？　バリアネットなんかじゃない
Is there something wrong with being retro? I'm not some barrier net
暗いのなんか嫌だったって　我慢してた
I hated the darkness, I was just putting up with it
吐いてみたって本音は死んでいた
Even when I vented, my true feelings were dead
選びたい　吸ってたい
I want to choose, I want to inhale
歪んでいくんだ　ぽかぽかの境界線
Distorting, a warm boundary line
イェイ　どれも正解で
Yay, everything is the correct answer
イェイ　どれも正解だ
選びたい　吸ってたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to choose, I want to inhale, it's distorting
マリオネットだから
Because I'm a marionette
期待したい　もっといいの　もっとつまんない　本気のシンデレラ
I want to expect something better, something more boring, a Cinderella in earnest
叶えたい　消えてたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to fulfill it, I want to disappear, it's distorting
ぽかぽかの境界線
A warm boundary line
イェイ　どれも正解で
Yay, everything is the correct answer
イェイ　どれも正解だ
叶えたい　消えてたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to fulfill it, I want to disappear, it's distorting
ぽかぽかの境界線
A warm boundary line
イェイ　どれも正解で
Yay, everything is the correct answer
イェイ　どれも正解だ
選びたい　吸ってたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to choose, I want to inhale, it's distorting
ぽかぽかの境界線
A warm boundary line
君だけに教えていいか
Can I tell only you?
そろそろもうどうでもいいか
Is it about time for it not to matter anymore?
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
死ぬ！
I'm gonna die!
死ぬよ俺もう、とんでもなくね...
I'm seriously gonna die, it's incredible...
息切れしてしまいますが、でもどうだった？
I'm out of breath, but how was it?
めちゃ良かったでしょ？
It was great, right?
めちゃくちゃカッコ良かったでしょ？
It was super cool, wasn't it?
ギター嬉しかったー、ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy with the guitar, thank you.
じゃあちょっと、このね、実は気付かなかったかも知れないですけど...
Well then, actually, you might not have noticed...
左右見てください、お立ち台があったりだとかね...
Look at the left and right, there are riser platforms...
そして今回なんとですね、ベースを弾いてくださったり、ドラムを叩いてくださり、
And for this time, thank you so much for playing the bass and drums.
本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ではちょっと、こちらのお立ち台に上りたいなって思うんで、
So, I want to go up on this platform,
見てみて、フェスと言えばこれだよね、みたいな。
so take a look. This is what a festival is all about.
どう？
How is it?
イエーイ、カッコいいっしょ？
Yay, cool, right?
このちょっと高いところから弾く感じも。
This feeling of playing from a high place too.
めっちゃテンション... あーみんな！応援してくれてありがとう！
I'm so pumped... Ah, everyone! Thanks for the support!
こっちのみんなもありがとう！
Thanks to everyone over here!
あっちのみんなにも行きましょうかね。
Let's go over to the folks on that side too.
ふー、ハアハア言ってる... 行くぜ！
Whew, I'm huffing and puffing... Here I go!
こっちや！
This way!
はいみんなー、こっちのみんなもどうだ？
Hi everyone, how are you guys over here?
盛り上がってるかー！
You having fun?!
ありがとうございました！めちゃめちゃギターカッコ良かったでしょ？
Thank you very much! The guitar was super cool, wasn't it?
本当にね、カッコいいギター貰えて嬉しいです。
I'm really happy to have received such a cool guitar.
坂又お誕生日プレゼント、ありがとうございました。
Sakamata's birthday present, thank you.
運営さんありがとうございました。
Management, thank you.
ではね、この後グッズ紹介したいと思いますので、一旦ちょっとギター置かせてしか？
Well then, I'd like to introduce the goods after this, so can I put the guitar down for a bit?
置きます。
I'm putting it down.
置かせてください。
Please let me.
置きましたー。
I put it down.
ということでですね、今回沙花叉クロヱ生誕祭のグッズが出ます！
So, the goods for Sakamata Chloe's birthday festival are coming out!
こちらです、ジャジャジャジャン！
Here they are, ta-dah!
ドン！沙花叉クロヱ誕生日記念2023！
Boom! Sakamata Chloe Birthday Celebration 2023!
沙花叉クロヱ 誕生日記念 2023
Sakamata Chloe Birthday Celebration 2023
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
テーマはね、お誕生日となっておりまして、
The theme is, well, birthday,
フィーバー沙花叉です。
it's 'Fever Sakamata'.
今回はね、色々な飼育員さんたちに手に取って欲しくて、
This time, I want all the Shikuin-san to be able to get them,
お求めやすい価格になっております。
so they're at an affordable price.
ではちょっと、一個ずつね、説明していきたいと思いまーす。
Now, I'd like to explain them one by one.
まずは、こちら！
First up, this one!
ドゥルルル... アクリルジオラマスタンド！
Drumroll... Acrylic Diorama Stand!
アクリルジオラマスタンド
Acrylic Diorama Stand
可愛いっしょ？
Cute, right?
めちゃめちゃ可愛い。
Super cute.
はい、フィーバー沙花叉のアクリルジオラマです。
Yes, it's the Fever Sakamata acrylic diorama.
パセリ先生、本当にいつもありがとうございます。
Paseri-sensei, thank you so much as always.
お忙しい中めちゃめちゃ可愛いく仕上げてくださり、本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you for making it so cute despite your busy schedule, really.
あの子多忙先生な、ありがとうございます。
She's a very busy teacher, thank you.
このアクスタに拝むとなんかフィーバーができるとか、
There's a superstition that praying to this stand will bring you 'fever',
なんとか迷信があるとかないとか知らんけど...
or maybe there isn't, I don't know...
はい、次はこちら！ドドン！
Okay, next is this! Ta-dah!
はい、ランダムアクリルキーホルダーです！
Yes, it's the Random Acrylic Keychains!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Random Acrylic Keychains
こちらなんと、ライブ中に使用したスロットデザインのアクリルキーホルダーになっております。
These are acrylic keychains with the slot machine designs used during the live show.
ランダム商品になっているので、運試しをしてみてください。
They're random items, so please try your luck.
沙花叉はね、多分「7」を三つね、こう繋げて、
I think it would be cool to, say, connect three '7's together,
トリプルセブン配置にしたりするのもいいかなって思ったり、
in a Triple Seven arrangement...
あとね、それぞれの組み合わせで役が作れますので、
Also, you can make 'hands' with each combination,
みんなちょっと楽しみにしててね、どれが当たるかワクワク。
so please look forward to it, it's exciting to see what you get.
飼育証明書
Breeding Certificate
はい。
Yes.
飼育証明書です。
It's a breeding certificate.
沙花叉の飼育証明書、こちら通勤通学のパスケースや社員証などね、
Sakamata's breeding certificate. You can put it in your pass case or ID holder,
あの、ぶら下げてるあれの中にぜひ入れてください。
the one you hang, so please put it in there.
裏側にはね、沙花叉が名前一応書いておきましたのでよろしくお願いします。
On the back, I wrote my name, so please take care of it.
さあ、続いてこちら。ドドン！
Now, next is this. Ta-dah!
リボンモチーフキーリング
Ribbon Motif Key Ring
リボンモチーフキーリングとなっております。こちら可愛いよね。
It's a ribbon motif key ring. This is cute, isn't it?
沙花叉の衣装にあるリボンのキーリングです。これ実は色んなところにあるんですけど、
It's a key ring of the ribbon on my outfit. Actually, it's in various places,
ちょっと探してみてください。どこだろどこだろ？
so please try to find it. Where is it, where is it?
どこどこどこだろ？ 探してね。
Where, where, where could it be? Look for it, okay?
そしてですね、鍵だけじゃなくてね、カバンとかにね、つけてもおしゃれな感じになると思いますので
And then, not just for keys, but even if you attach it to a bag or something, I think it will look stylish,
ぜひとも、いい感じのね、さりげないグッズなのでつけてみてください。
so please do try attaching it, as it's a nice, subtle piece of merch.
記念ボイス
Commemorative Voices
そしてボイスもございます。ドドン！
And there are also voices. Ta-dah!
記念ボイス「最高に激アツな誕生日」ということで、ぜひ聞いてください。
Commemorative voice "The Most Intense Birthday", so please give it a listen.
どんな内容なんだって、もちろんね、
As for what the content is, of course...
フルセットもご用意させていただいております。ドドーン！
we have also prepared a full set. Ta-daaah!
誕生日記念フルセット
Birthday Commemorative Full Set
ジャーン！ 全部セットコンプしていただきますと、
Ta-da! If you complete the whole set...
特典として複製サインに一言メッセージを直筆で書きたいと思います。
as a bonus, I'll write a short message by hand on the duplicated signature.
コンプ特典ボイスはですね、通常ボイスと別にね、もう一個ついてくる
The completion bonus voice is, in addition to the regular voice, another one...
「君と最高の時間」というボイスになっておりますので、
called "The Best Time With You",
ぜひとも皆さん、よろしくお願いいたします。イェイイェイイェイ！
so everyone, please check it out. Yay yay yay!
10時から発売ですね。よろしくお願いします。
It goes on sale from 10 o'clock. Thank you.
はい。次が最後の曲になるということで、
Yes. Since the next one will be the last song,
みんなこの曲にちょっと聞いたらびっくりすると思うんですけれども、
I think everyone will be a bit surprised when they hear this song, but...
ちょっとみんながびっくりしてくれるのをわくわく期待しながら歌いたいと思います。
I want to sing it while excitedly looking forward to everyone being surprised.
では、聞いてください。
Now, please listen.
パラライズ。
Paralyze.
パパパラライズ
Pa-pa-paralyze
パラライズ
Paralyze
調子合わせて笑う
Singing along with the mood and laughing
その度に嘲笑う
Sneering every time I do
もう一人の自分が居る
There is another me
パパパラライズ
Pa-pa-paralyze
超幸せな振りも
Pretending to be super happy
傷ついてる振りも
Pretending to be hurt
見透かされてるような
Feeling like I'm being seen through
パパパラライズ
Pa-pa-paralyze
自己嫌悪なら いつもいつもいつも
When it comes to self-loathing, it's always, always, always
自嘲するにも 恐れ恐れ
Even when I'm self-deprecating, I'm afraid, afraid
スタンバイ 今はスリーパー
Standby, now I'm a sleeper
明日またノックして ノックしてよ
Knock again tomorrow, please knock
大嫌いなんだよ面汚し
I hate you so much, you disgrace
ハローハロー 不幸不幸
Hello, hello, misery, misery
自分の端をかじり笑う
Gnawing on the edges of myself and laughing
鏡越しのOh Oh グラスホッパー
The grasshopper in the mirror, oh oh
それで結構 共存可能？ 不可能？
Is that enough? Is coexistence possible? Impossible?
途方に暮れ 飽きが来たら
When I'm at a loss and boredom sets in
パパパラライズ 麻痺らせて
Pa-pa-paralyze, make me numb
ラウンドアバウト メズマライズ
Roundabout, mesmerize
逆しまに狂って アップサイドダウン
Go crazy in reverse, upside down
だったらララバイ
Then a lullaby
自分同士パラライズ
Paralyzing each other
自己嫌悪する いつかいつかいつか
I'll loathe myself someday, someday, someday
遠目に見れば 喜劇喜劇
Seen from afar, it's a comedy, a comedy
涙はいつも 真珠みたい
Tears are always like pearls
ほらノックして ノックしてよ
Look, knock, please knock
大嫌いなんだよ面汚し
I hate you so much, you disgrace
ハローハロー 不幸不幸
Hello, hello, misery, misery
自分の端をかじり笑う
Gnawing on the edges of myself and laughing
鏡越しのOh Oh グラスホッパー
The grasshopper in the mirror, oh oh
それで結構 共存可能？ 不可能？
Is that enough? Is coexistence possible? Impossible?
途方に暮れ 飽きが来たら
When I'm at a loss and boredom sets in
パパパラライズ 麻痺らせた
Pa-pa-paralyze, it made me numb
それは切なさだった
It was a feeling of sorrow
夜を深く泳いだら 三日月の香りのする
Swimming deep into the night, smelling like a crescent moon
命を惹き剥いて
Stripping away life
Cry gonna cry
猛烈にまたたく
Flickering fiercely
パラライズ パラライズ
Paralyze, paralyze
共存可能？ 不可能？
Is coexistence possible? Impossible?
パパパラライズ 麻痺らせて
Pa-pa-paralyze, make me numb
And lies
パラライズ And lies
Paralyze and lies
パラライズ
Paralyze
はいということで、
Alright, everyone!
今歌いました新オリ曲のパラライズがですね、
My new original song, "Paralyze," which I just sang,
このあと10時15分から
will have its premiere
プレミア公開になります！
at 10:15 PM!
お楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
みんな応援してくれてありがとう！
Thank you all so much for your support!
ごちそうさまでしたー！
Thank you for watching!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!